四川省自贡市，初二零二零届
毕业生学业考试英语听力部分
做题时，可将答案画在试卷上。
录音内容结束后，你将有两分钟的时间将试卷上的答案转涂到。
答题卡上。
第一节，听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，从每题所给的
,B Hello, Mary.
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试。
卷的相应位置。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
听下面一段材料，回答。
第一小题。
听下面一段材料，回答第二小题。
听下面一段材料，回答第三小题。
听下面一段材料，回答第四小题。
听下面一段材料，回答第五小题。
What kind of TV shows do you like?
I can't stand Beijing operas and sitcoms, but I like sports shows.
They are exciting and interesting.
第二节，听下面几段对话或独白。
每段对话或独白。
然后有一个或几个小题，从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒。
秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间，每段对话或读白读两遍。
听下面一段材料，回答第六小题。
My father prepares a big meal for all of us.
听下面一段材料，回答第七小题。
Tom, did you do anything exciting on vacation?
Actually, I went to Russia.
What about you, Oh, we just hung out on the beach.
And we went to the movies.
That kind of thing.
Tom, did you do anything exciting on vacation?
Actually, I went to Russia.
What about you, Jane?
we just hung out on the beach.
And we went to the movies.
That kind of thing.
听下面一段材料，回答第八小题。
Lucy, it's time for supper.
What are you doing now?
I can't find my notebook.
Have you seen it anywhere?
Sorry, I haven't.
Why not ask your mother?
Maybe she's seen it.
Lucy, it's time for supper.
What are you doing now?
I can't find my notebook.
Have you seen it anywhere?
I haven't. Why not ask your mother?
Maybe she's seen it.
听下面一段材料，回答第九小题。
Would you like to be a green person?
Of course, I'd like to.
But what should I do?
You must turn off the lights when you leave a room.
Would you like to be a green person?
Of course, I'd like to.
But what should I do?
You must turn off the when you leave a room.
听下面一段材料，回答第十。
小题。
Take care of my child.
My cell phone is missing.
I must go to the lost and found office.
听下面一段材料，回答第十一至十二题。
Oh, look! Someone left his backpack on the floor.
Whose backpack do you think this is?
I don't know.
Oh, here is a basketball.
And someone wrote a letter J on it.
It seems that the owner's name begins with J.
Yes, but it can't be John.
He isn't at school today.
It could belong to Jax.
He likes playing basketball, and he always forgets things.
Wait a French book.
It must be Jimmy's backpack.
He likes playing basketball, and he's the only one in our class who's studying
French. Oh, look!
Someone left his backpack on the floor.
Whose backpack do you think this is?
I don't know.
Oh, here is a basketball.
And someone wrote a letter J on it.
It seems that the owner's name begins with J.
Yes, but it can't be John.
He isn't at school today.
It could belong to Jax.
He likes playing basketball, and he always forgets things.
Wait a French book.
It must be Jimmy's backpack.
He likes playing basketball, and he's the only one in our class who's studying
French. My manager told me never to go to work again.
听下面一段材料，回答第十三至十五题。
I can't believe it.
Why? I don't know.
When he told me that, I was really surprised.
Were you often late for work?
Yes, I was.
Did you often think about other things when you were working?
Sometimes. Can you use a computer?
No, I can't.
Well, I think I know why.
You didn't make good use of your time, and you didn't try to learn new things.
Well, think You didn't make good use of your time, didn't time, Well, I I make of
time, Well, I think I know why.
You didn't make good use of your time, and you didn't try to learn new things.
听下面一段独白，回答第十六至二十题。
boys and girls!
Hello, Welcome to Teen Time!
Today, I'd like to talk about swimming.
Swimming is very popular in summer.
People like it because water makes them feel cool.
If you like swimming in the river or sea, it may not be safe.
In recent years, about 10,000 people died while they were enjoying themselves in the
water. And most of them were students.
But some people are still not careful when swimming.
They often think they can swim so well that nothing can happen to them in the water.
Now summer is coming again.
If you go swimming, please pay attention to the safety.
Firstly, don't get into the water when you are alone.
Secondly, if there's a no swimming sign, don't get into the water either.
Thirdly, don't drink before swimming.
Fourthly, it is also, remember, not to eat any food while swimming as you can't
breathe easily. And fifthly, you should know about the weather before going out for
a swim. Stop swimming if the weather is bad.
If you follow the safety advice, you will be safer.
You will enjoy swimming more.
boys and girls.
Welcome to Teen Time.
Today I'd like to talk about swimming.
Swimming is very popular in summer.
People like it because water makes them feel cool.
If you like swimming in the river or sea, it may not be safe.
In recent years, about 10,000 people died while they were enjoying themselves in the
water. And most of them were students.
But some people are still not careful when swimming.
They often think they can swim so well that nothing can happen to them in the water.
Now summer is coming again.
If you go swimming, please pay attention to the safety.
Firstly, don't get into the water when you are alone.
Secondly, if there's a no swimming sign, don't get into the water either.
Thirdly, don't drink before swimming.
Fourthly, it is also, remember, not to eat any food while swimming as you can't
breathe easily. And fifthly, you should know about the weather before going out for
a swim. Stop swimming if the weather is bad.
If you follow the safety advice, you will be safer.
You will enjoy swimming more.
Thank you for
听力到此结束。